Junior Gameplay Engineer

Email: benrosewastaken@gmail.com | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/benrwastaken

Portfolio: wzrdistaken.github.io | GitHub: github.com/WzrdIsTaken

JoerrideEntityComponents(std::vector<ComponentDatax& componentData,
 ntt::hashed\_string const propertyComponentRef, entt::hashed\_string const
 ropertyData const const propertyDataOverride) NABI\_NOEXCEPT

// Loop through all of the component's properties defined in xml
for (ComponentData& componentData : componentData)

{
 // If the property is referencing this component
 if (componentData.m\_Id == propertyComponentRef)

{
 // Foreach property on that component
 for (PropertyData& propertyData : componentData.m\_Properties)
 // If we find the property, override it
 if (propertyData.m\_Id == propertyData.m\_p

abi::Reflection::Creation

## **PROFILE**

I am a undergraduate Gameplay Engineer with a year's industry experience at Playground Games using C++ & C# to develop Forza Horizon 5 and its Rally Adventure DLC. Key to my role was ensuring the stability of the game using player emulation testing through Microsoft's Intelligent Bot Automation toolset.

I am set to graduate from the University of the West of England in 2024 with a first class in Games Technology (BSc Hons). Here I have gained 3 years of practical experience with both object oriented and data driven development. I have completed solo and team projects using C++, C#, DirectX and Unity (see my portfolio) and have been recognised for excellence by inclusion on the Dean's list.

To further develop my skills I have also undertaken personal projects including a <u>custom C++ engine</u> with DirectX and an Entity Component System, and created my own full release game "<u>Wardens Teddy</u>".

I am now seeking to continue my career in the games industry as a Gameplay Engineer.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Playground Games** — Gameplay Engineer

June 2022 - PRESENT, Leamington Spa

- C++ & C# development in bespoke engine for Forza Horizon 5 on the Gameplay and Live teams.
- Shipped Horizon Rally Adventure DLC on Xbox and PC.
- Investigated, planned and produced end to end automated testing solution using BotBrain.
- Collaborated internationally with Microsoft Studios based in the USA and Poland.
- Planned and costed tasks, working within team sprints.
- Presented developed features to stakeholders.

#### **University of the West of England** — C++ Mentor

September 2021 - May 2022, Bristol

- Planned and ran code support sessions for first and second year Games Technology students.
- Earned the <a href="ILM Award">ILM Award</a> in Effective Mentoring.
- Secured my own industrial placement, then gave a presentation to the following year group detailing my experiences and recommending strategies to adopt.

### **SKILLS**

#### Technical

C++, C#, Version Control (Perforce/Git), Testing, Continuous Integration (TeamCity), Visual Studio

#### **Engines**

Bespoke C++ Engine @ Playground, DirectX (own engine), Unity, Unreal / Visual Scripting

#### Personal

Teamwork, Communication, Presentation, Planning, Time Management

#### Miscellaneous

Python, Power BI, Kusto, Web (HTML/CSS/JS), Teams/Office Suite

## **EDUCATION**

# University of the West of England — Games Technology BSc (Hons)

UWE is TIGA Accredited

September 2020 - June 2024, Bristol

Working Grade: 1st Class

### **Lord Williams School** — A Level & GCSE

September 2013 - June 2020, Thame

- 3 A Levels, grade A, including Computer Science (A)
- 9 GCSEs, grades 7-8, including Maths (7) and English (8)

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Achieved inclusion on the Dean's List for first-class working grade across all university modules.

Completed ILM Level 3 effective mentoring scheme.

Completed all levels of the <u>Duke of Edinburgh's Award</u>, including Gold.

Competed in swimming at a national level.

## **HOBBIES**

Running, Climbing, Travel, Programming, Korean, Reading, Swimming, Playing Games

## **REFERENCES**

Peter Scorgie - Associate Lead Engineer @ Playground Games - peter.scorgie@playground-games.com
Lloyd Savickas - Games Technology Programme Leader @ UWE - lloyd.savickas@uwe.ac.uk